#### GRADUATE RESEARCHER · MASTERS STUDENT

Beirut, Lebanon

□ (+961) 71-778924 | wissam.antoun@gmail.com | 🖸 WissamAntoun | 🛅 wissamantoun | 🞓 Wissam Antoun

## Summary\_

Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Engineer specialised in state-of-the-art Natural Language Processing techniques. Within 1 year, I had developed my knowledge of NLP and published one the most famous and powerful AI models for Arabic text representation. I also ranked in top places in almost all AI competitions that i participated in. In addition, I have 2 years of experience in teaching as a Graduate Teaching Assistant at the Eng. faculty at AUB and through online sessions. I'm self-motivated, self-taught and a performer when working on tight deadlines. I'm also a tech geek who loves computer hardware and technology, and enjoys DIY projects and gaming.

# Work Experience\_

**Zaka** Online

Al Instructor May, 2020 - Current

Developed and delivered training on AI and ML topics including Natural Language Processing

Stars of Science Doha, Oatar

MACHINE LEARNING EXPERT Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2020

Provided ML and Al solutions to contestants as part of the support team

#### MIND Lab (Prof. Hazem Hajj) -American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT Sep. 2018 - Current

Research focuses on SOTA NLP technologies and social chatbots.

# ECE Dept. - American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanoi

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Feb. 2018 Dec. 2018
- EECE 435L: Software Tools Lab, Co-Instructor (3 semesters)
- EECE 696: Applied Parallel Programming, Lab instructor (1 semester)
- EECE 330: Data Structures and Algorithms, Lab instructor (1 semester)

# Huawei Technologies (Lebanon) S.A.R.L.

Beirut, Lebanon

INTERN June 2016 - Aug. 2016

Learned about various LTE principles, base station hardware, and Microwave transmissions systems.

# **Publications**

AraBERT: Transformer-based Model for Arabic Language Understanding. *Antoun, Wissam, Fady Baly, and Hazem Hajj Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020*, 2020, Marseille, France

Multi-Task Learning using AraBert for Offensive Language Detection. Djandji, Marc, Fady Baly, **Wissam Antoun**, and Hazem Hajj Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020, 2020, Marseille, France

State of the Art Models for Fake News Detection Tasks. *Antoun, Wissam*, Fady Baly, Rim Achour, Amir Hussein, and Hazem Hajj 2020 IEEE International Conference on Informatics, IoT, and Enabling Technologies (ICIoT) (ICIoT'2020), 2020, Doha, Qatar

hULMonA: The Universal Language Model in Arabic. *ElJundi, Obeida, Wissam Antoun, Nour El Droubi, Hazem Hajj, Wassim El-Hajj, and Khaled Shaban Proceedings of the Fourth Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop at ACL*, 2019, Florence, Italy

A Comprehensive Approach for A Smart Medication Dispenser. *Kassem, Abdallah, Wissam Antoun, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary International Journal of Computing and Digital Systems* 8.02 (2019) pp. 131–141. University of Bahrain, 2019

Smart Medicine Dispenser (SMD). *Antoun, Wissam,* Ali Abdo, Suleiman Al-Yaman, Abdallah Kassem, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary 2018 IEEE 4th Middle East Conference on Biomedical Engineering (MECBME), 2018

Real-Time Fire Detection Using CUDA. *Antoun, Wissam* and Manal JalloulISC High Performance, Poster Presentation, 2019, Frankfurt, Germany

#### Honors & Awards

**Second Place**, OSACT4-Shared task on Offensive

Language Detection, 2020

France

Best Domain Detection system, Qatar

International Fake News Detection and Annotation Doha, Qatar Contest, 2019

**Second Place**, Mindsets-OLX Datathon, Best car price prediction score. kaggle.com/c/mindsets, 2019

AUB, Lebanon

**First place**, Big Data, AI, and Media Hackathon Powered by Touch and Anghami, 2019

AUB, Lebanon

### **Presentations**

#### **High Performance Computing for Lebanon**

(HPC4L) Brown Bag, Presented the use case of HPC

Beirut,
for pretraining transformer-based model for Arabic

Lebanon

language Understanding for HPC4L, Feb. 2020

**PyData Khobar meetup**, Presenter for AraBERT:

pretraining, use cases and future improvements,
May. 2012

Online

# Education

# Masters Of Eng. In Electrical And Computer Engineering

Beirut, Lebanon

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT

Feb. 2018 - Aug. 2020

- Major Area: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning systems
- Minro Area: Software, Networking and Security
- Awarded Graduate Fellowship with full tuition coverage

## Bachelor Of Eng. In Computer And Communication Engineering

Zouk Mosbeh, Lebanon

NOTRE DAME UNIVERSITY - LOUAIZE

Fall. 2014 - Summer 2017

• GPA: 3.58 Dean's List for 6 semesters

# **Skills**

Python TensorFlow PyTorch Keras	Bash Git CUDA
Parallel Programming C++ C# Matlab	Java SQL LaTex
VSCode	